[Music]
kidney Friendly Foods for a healthy
detox and cleansing in natural way our
kidneys carry out significant and potent
functions when they are in good health
our kidneys which are frequently
disregarded work tirelessly to remove
waste and extra fluid from our blood and
we can provide them with the assistance
they require to perform at their Peak by
including the appropriate nutrients in
our diet
this can improve our skin increase our
energy levels and even help us lose
weight in addition to improving kidney
function to keep these vital organs
functioning optimally we need to provide
them with the right
nutrients let's give them the support
they
deserve discover the power of Nature's
Pharmacy foods that can help cleanse and
detoxify your kidneys promoting overall
health and
vitality let's start with fruits number
one cranberries cranberries are low in
calories and high in vitamins c and e
fiber and antioxidants it has benefits
to the urinary
tract cranberries contain compounds
called
proanthocyanidins which prevent bacteria
from adhering to the walls of the
urinary
tract this can help reduce the risk of
urinary tract infections UTI which can
lead to kidney infections if not
treated the antioxidants and cranberries
help reduce oxidative stress it may
contain a mild diuretic properties
helping to promote urine production and
flush out toxins a 2016 review of 34
preclinical studies revealed that
Cranberries or compounds in cranberries
had several benefits triggering the
death of cancer cells slowing the growth
of cancer cells and reducing
inflammation a simple recipe is
cranberry sauce or Cranberry Jam for
your bread number two apples apples are
a good source of fiber particularly
soluble fiber like pectin as well as
Vitamin C low potass ium phosphorus
sodium as content and various
phytochemicals apples are high in
antioxidants which help reduce
inflammation and oxidative stress in the
body people with kidney disease should
limit high potassium fruits it help to
maintain acidity and urine and prevent
the growth of bacteria inside the
kidneys either you can eat the apple raw
make it into an apple pie or drink as
apple juice it contains 20 Mig of
phosphorus and 195 mg of potassium are
found in one medium-sized Apple it may
lessen constipation and help decrease
blood sugar and cholesterol levels
number three
blueberries blueberries are high in
vitamin C and K fiber and antioxidants
particularly
anthocyanins a 1 or 2 cup serving of
blueberries contains less than 150 mg of
potassium has 40 calories with about 2 G
of fiber it has low in sodium and
phosphorus
basically it is suitable for consumption
by patients undergoing hemodialysis
perianal dialysis chronic renal disease
and kidney stones they have powerful
antioxidants that can help protect the
kidneys from oxidative damage and they
help reduce inflammation that is really
beneficial to the body and kidneys
blueberries are yearr round
nutrient-dense and simple to make the
price of fresh blueberries varies with
the season although frozen blueberries
are frequently less expensive rinse then
eat number four
strawberries a superfood that is low in
calories and high in fiber fate
manganese vitamin C and antioxidants is
the
strawberry they are excellent for people
who have chronic kidney disease diets
since they are low in
potassium it is very low in calories
providing only 28 calories 6.5 G of
carbohydrates low potassium food
containing 100 to 30 m Wat for 1 NR 2
cup and 2 G of fiber for 1 NR 2 cup of
sliced berries these sweet berries can
be blended into a Fresh Smoothie added
to salads sauces yogurt oatmeal cereal
or dipped in dark chocolate number five
pomegranates antioxidants are abundant
in pomegranates which are tart and sweet
fruits because pomegranates are rich in
fiber folate potassium Vitamin K Vitamin
E
and vitamin B6 eating them may offer
numerous health benefits additionally
they contain three times as many
antioxidants which have been found to
lower inflammation than green
tea antioxidants found in pomegranates
can help lower inflammation and
oxidative stress this may enhance renal
function and reduce creatinine
levels according to studies pomegranate
juice consumption can help those with
chronic kidney disease CKD have better
renal function
prevent problems in kidney disease
patients reduce the chance of infections
in hemodialysis patients in terms of
promoting Kidney Health vegetables are
equally as crucial as fruits number six
beets beetroots or simply beets are
bright red root vegetables that are
prized for their deep red color earthy
flavor and plenty of vitamins and
minerals high in fiber folate potassium
manganese iron and vitamin C B beats are
low in
calories red and purple beets are high
in an anti-inflammatory compound known
as beetal
Lanes nitrates found in beets have the
ability to increase renal blood flow and
decrease blood pressure both of which
are essential for kidney
function the liver May benefit from
bealin which can lessen the strain on
the kidneys and Aid in blood
detoxification consuming beetroot juice
is believed to raise nitric oxide levels
in the body which can enhance lung and
muscular function function blood flow
and cardiorespiratory
endurance the advantages of beets will
appeal to you if you enjoy intense
workouts number seven garlic a member of
the aliam family garlic has been used in
cooking for Millennia and is known to
have anti-inflammatory and antioxidant
qualities many of the health advantages
of garlic can be attributed to its
abundance of sulfur compounds manganese
and vitamin C and B6 black Garlic's
Organo sulfur component and flavonoid
content are strong antioxidants and
anti-glycation agents that help repair
kidney and liver cells by boosting the
activity of antioxidant enzymes like
glutathione peroxidase catalis and
superoxide dismutase garlic has potent
anti-inflammatory properties that can
help reduce inflammation in the kidneys
and throughout the body garlic can
assist the body eliminate waste and
pollutants by increasing the production
of urine since high blood pressure is a
key risk factor for kidney disease
garlic may help lower blood pressure
which is crucial For Kidney Health
number eight spinach a nutrient-dense
leafy green vegetable spinach is rich in
minerals like iron magnesium and folate
in addition to vitamins a c and k
antioxidants like lutein and ZX Onin are
also abundant in it the antioxidants in
spinach can help protect the kidneys
from damage caused by free radicals
spinach contains various phytonutrients
that can help reduce inflammation
because of its high vitamin and
antioxidant content which can support
healthy kidney function by helping with
blood filtration spinach has a high
water content which AIDS in hydration
and helps promote kidney function by
encouraging urine
production crucial factors to take into
account although spinach has many health
benefits its high potassium content can
be problematic for those who have kidney
disease because their systems may not be
able to adequately eliminate excess
potassium from the blood number nine
cauliflower cauliflower is low in
calories and high in fiber vitamin C K
and B6 as well as folate and
antioxidants it aids in the removal of
toxins from your body a kidney friendly
substitute for mashed potatoes is
cauliflower that has been steamed and
mashed it has substances that Aid in the
body's
detoxification and may promote Liver
Health which benefits the kidneys
indirectly it has anti oxidants such as
Vitamin C which supports kidney function
and lowers inflammation cauliflower or
brussel sprouts Are alkaline foods
making your diet less acidic and
providing less pressure on your kidneys
number 10 red bell peppers around the
world bell peppers also referred to as
capsicum or sweet peppers are utilized
in many different Cuisines bell peppers
can be red yellow orange or green among
other colors this is a kidney friendly
summer vegetable that doesn't dissolve
OLS olve when eaten red bell peppers are
rich in vitamins a c and B6 folate and
antioxidants bell peppers contain
various antioxidants like lycopene
especially in red peppers which can help
combat oxidative stress and can help
protect against cell
damage you can eat bell peppers raw as
an appetizer or in a salad additionally
it can be prepared as gravies added to
any morning dish or roasted and used as
a sandwich topping for a main core first
fill peppers and bake them cut them for
an omelet or add them to grilled kebabs
number 11 broccoli a cruciferous
vegetable high in nutrients broccoli has
several significant Health advantages
being a rich source of antioxidants it
may improve blood sugar regulation lower
inflammation increase immunity and
support heart
health numerous minerals including as
fiber potassium iron vitamin C and
vitamin K are abundant in broccoli
with only 27 calories per one o two cup
broccoli is incredibly low in calories
both raw and cooked broccoli are
delicious broccoli contains as much
vitamin C as an orange in one cup one
cup of broccoli has roughly 60 mg of
calcium making it an excellent non-dairy
source of the
mineral number 12 flax and chia seeds
because flax and chia seeds are low in
sodium potassium and phosphorus they are
regarded as kidney friendly they are ALS
also rich in antioxidants fiber and good
fats the high fiber content of flax and
chia seeds can help decrease cholesterol
support gastrointestinal health and keep
you feeling full flax and chia seeds can
be added to hot porridge yogurt salads
baked products and
smoothies flax seeds can be ground to
improve absorption to keep flax and chia
seeds from spoiling store them in the
freezer in a well sealed
container number 13 nuts and seeds nuts
and seeds can be good for kidney health
because include a variety of healthful
components including fiber plant protein
vitamin E antioxidants heart healthy
fats Omega-3s plant steril and
more many nuts contain antioxidants like
vitamin E which can help fight
inflammation and oxidative
damage plant steril and other minerals
found in nuts have anti-inflammatory
properties monounsaturated and
polyunsaturated ated fats are examples
of good fats found in the majority of
nuts and
seeds number 14 green teas drinking a
cup of green tea is a simple technique
to Aid with your body's
detoxification green tea contains a lot
of cakin cakin are a particular kind of
polyphenol a type of antioxidants that
boost detox
enzymes the kidney cells May benefit
from these antioxidants ability to fight
off dangerous free radicals which are
unstable chemicals in the body that can
cause inflammation and cellular
damage calcium crystallization and
kidney stone formation are inhibited by
cakin number 15 eggs mainly because they
are a highquality protein Source
especially when eating only the whites
of the egg which are low in phosphorus
and thought to be a better option for
people with kidney issues this way
people can meet their protein needs
while putting as little strain on their
kidneys as
possible phosphorus levels in egg white
are significantly lower eggs contain
many vitamins and minerals including
vitamins a d e k folate selenium and B
vitamins and choline a type of fat that
is key for proper cell function eggs can
be consumed in a variety of ways such as
scrambled poached hard-boiled or in an
omelet they can also be deved or used to
casseres meatloaf or crab cakes as a
binder and to boost the protein content
they can be eaten on a salad or in an
egg salad sandwich
number 16 fish fish come in a wide
variety all fish are a great source of
high quality protein but some are better
sources of omega-3 fatty acids we must
obtain omega-3 fatty acids from our food
because our bodies are unable to
manufacture them fish is a good source
of protein without being high in
saturated
fat just a three o portion of fish the
size of a deck of cards provides an
average of 20 g of protein
minerals such as calcium phosphorus iron
zinc iodine magnesium and potassium are
abundant in
it omega-3 fatty acids found in fish may
help your kidneys by reducing your risk
of developing chronic kidney disease
CKD reduce the rate at which renal
function deteriorates reduce blood
pressure reduce levels of triglycerides
in the kidneys heart and blood vessels
number 17 healthy oils and fats healthy
oils and fats include those rich in
monounsaturated and polyunsaturated
fatty
acids bad fats include industrial made
trans fat and saturated
fats to prevent consuming too many
calories we must restrict the amount of
fat in our diet our diets contain fat
which is a significant source of energy
calories and AIDS in the absorption of
certain vitamins and
minerals healthy fats and oils are also
vital because f f is necessary for blood
coagulation muscle contraction
inflammation reduction and the
development of cell membranes and nerve
tissue by reducing LDL cholesterol
healthy oils and fats may help reduce
the risk of atherosclerosis and heart
disease some examples of healthy oils
that can be purchased at our nearest
supermarket are avocado oil olive oil
canula oil and grape seed oil here are
some behaviors that can help maintain
the health of your kidneys number number
hydration The Academy of nutrition and
dietetics states that about 60% of an
adult human's body weight is made up of
water water is necessary for the proper
operation of every organ including the
liver and brain for the kidneys to
effectively remove extra waste drinking
adequate water is crucial and this is
particularly true during a kidney
cleanse study states that adult males
should consume 15.5 cups 3.7 L of fluid
per day while adult ladies should
consume 11.5 cups 2.7
L however this could change based on a
number of variables including your age
level of physical activity and whether
you have a medical condition that
affects
you number 19 quitting
smoking quitting smoking can have many
health benefits it improves circulation
in the renal arteries reducing any
formation of kidney
stones a better cardiovascular health
that your blood pressure and heart rate
both decline in a matter of days which
beneficial to your kidneys reducing
pressure on small vein and
arteries as soon as you stop smoking
your body starts to heal the Damage Done
and benefits last for
years number 20 don't drink alcohol
alcohol can alter renal function and
reduce the kidneys capacity to filter
blood your kidneys perform numerous
vital functions in addition to filtering
blood maintaining Ain the proper level
of water in your body is one of these
tasks because the kidneys are made to
retain water alcohol dehydrates the body
which can put stress on them drinking
alcohol increases the production of
reactive oxygen species R which can harm
renal cells mitochondria and antioxidant
capability the chance of renal disease a
chronic illness that does not get better
with time is doubled by heavy drinking
remember that even though these Foods
may be good for your kidneys you should
always speak with a doctor or trained
dietitian to develop a customized diet
plan maintaining ideal kidney function
requires a healthy diet consistent
exercise and enough fluids you may
Empower yourself to live a longer
healthier Life by prioritizing your
health and making educated decisions the
information provided on this channel is
for educational purposes only and is not
a substitute for professional medical
advice diagnosis or
treatment always consult with your
healthcare provider before making any
decis decisions related to your health